Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're talking a little bit about more small talk.
我是Catherine，今天我们继续聊聊闲聊的话题。
That's right.
没错。
We're going to continue our series.
我们将继续这个系列。
This is part nine, so we're coming close to the end of our 10-part series.
这是第九部分，所以我们快接近这个十部分系列的尾声了。
And today we're following Melissa and Michelle as they discuss very casually their personal
今天，我们跟随Melissa和Michelle，她们非常随意地讨论自己的个人
life specifically about their marriages or getting married.
生活，特别是关于婚姻或结婚的事情。
That's right.
没错。
So this one's a little bit more difficult than the last few.
所以这一部分比前几部分稍微难一点。
Let's take a listen to the dialogue and when we come back we'll be talking about some of
让我们先听一下对话，等我们回来后会讨论一些
those phrases that you heard.
你听到的那些短语。
Hey, Michelle.
嘿，Michelle。
Jump in quick.
快上车。
It's pouring out there.
外面下着倾盆大雨。
Oh, hi, Melissa.
哦，嗨，Melissa。
Are you going to the conference too?
你也要去会议吗？
I was planning to pick up Mr. Campbell.
我本来打算去接Campbell先生。
Yes, he told me.
是的，他告诉我了。
We need to pick him up at his hotel and then go to the conference.
我们需要去他酒店接他，然后去会议。
Oh, I see.
哦，我明白了。
Okay.
好的。
So I heard you got married.
所以我听说你结婚了。
Congratulations.
恭喜。
Oh, thank you.
哦，谢谢。
I'm very excited.
我非常兴奋。
We were going to get married next year, but then we decided to get married on holiday
我们本来打算明年结婚，但后来决定在假期里结婚
instead.
了。
It was wonderful.
那真是太棒了。
That sounds so romantic.
听起来真浪漫。
Jack and I were hoping to get married in Europe next year, but we had to postpone our plans.
Jack和我本来希望明年在欧洲结婚，但我们不得不推迟计划。
We just don't have the money.
我们就是没钱。
I know what you mean.
我明白你的意思。
I think Shanghai is getting more and more expensive.
我觉得上海越来越贵了。
Don't you?
你不觉得吗？
I sure do.
我确实觉得。
In my opinion, it's actually becoming more expensive than back home.
在我看来，它实际上比家乡还贵。
Definitely.
绝对是。
Oh, there's Mr. Campbell.
哦，Campbell先生来了。
Driver, can you stop here, please?
司机，能在这里停一下吗？
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So a lot of interesting phrases in this dialogue more than vocab.
这段对话中有很多有趣的短语，不仅仅是词汇。
So we're going to have two fluency builders.
所以我们要有两个流利度提升环节。
Let's start with the first one now.
现在开始第一个。
Fluency Builder.
流利度提升。
The first phrase in today's fluency builder is the phrase jump in.
今天流利度提升的第一个短语是“jump in”。
So Melissa says, hey, Michelle, jump in quick.
所以Melissa说，嘿，Michelle，快上车。
That's right.
没错。
So Melissa is actually in a taxi and that's why she's saying jump in quick.
所以Melissa实际上在出租车里，这就是为什么她说快上车。
So she is directing Michelle to do something.
所以她是在指示Michelle做某事。
She's saying jump in.
她说“jump in”。
So it's actually her telling Melissa, get in the car.
实际上她是在告诉Melissa，上车。
That's right.
没错。
And so we can use this phrase to jump in somewhere, which means you're going to do it very quickly.
所以我们可以用这个短语表示快速进入某个地方，意思是你会很快地做这件事。
Yeah, to go somewhere, to get in a place very quickly.
是的，去某个地方，很快地进入一个地方。
We could say it about a cab, but we could also say it about a swimming pool.
我们可以说关于出租车，但也可以说关于游泳池。
Maybe I'm swimming in the water and I say, Marco, jump in.
也许我在水里游泳，我说，Marco，跳进来。
The water's nice.
水很舒服。
That's right.
没错。
Or maybe you just got back from the gym and you're going to jump in the shower really
或者你刚从健身房回来，你要很快地冲个澡
quick and before you go out again.
然后再出门。
You're not actually going to jump like you jump the action, but you're going to get into
你实际上不会像动作那样跳，但你会很快地进入
the shower very quickly.
淋浴间。
That's right.
没错。
And of course, Melissa tells Michelle to jump in the cab quickly because it's pouring out
当然，Melissa告诉Michelle快上出租车，因为外面下着倾盆大雨
there.
。
It's pouring.
下着倾盆大雨。
What's pouring?
什么在倾泻？
The rain.
雨。
Pouring water, pouring wine.
倒水，倒酒。
That's right.
没错。
It's actually, yeah, it's pouring water out there.
实际上，是的，外面在下倾盆大雨。
It means it's raining very, very hard.
意思是雨下得非常大。
Okay, so it's not just drizzling a little, little bit.
好的，所以不只是下点毛毛雨。
It's raining very hard.
雨下得很大。
It's pouring rain.
下着倾盆大雨。
Okay, so we don't have to say the word rain.
好的，所以我们不必说“rain”这个词。
We can just say it's pouring.
我们可以只说“it's pouring”。
That's right.
没错。
As you can see in that sentence, Melissa doesn't say at any time it's raining, but we understand
正如你在那句话中看到的，Melissa任何时候都没说下雨，但我们明白。
that when somebody says it's pouring out there, you know that it means it's raining very hard.
当有人说“外面下着倾盆大雨”时，你就知道那意味着雨下得很大。
Can't be chocolate.
不可能是巧克力。
Can't be chocolate, can't be dogs or cats, right?
不可能是巧克力，也不可能是狗或猫，对吧？
No.
不是。
All right, so Michelle gets in the cab and she says, well, we have to pick up Mr. Campbell.
好的，所以米歇尔上了出租车，她说，嗯，我们得去接坎贝尔先生。
And Melissa says, yep, we need to pick him up at the hotel.
梅丽莎说，是的，我们需要去酒店接他。
All right, the verb here is to pick up.
好的，这里的动词是“pick up”。
Now we want to just remember this as a phrasal verb.
现在我们想把它记住为一个短语动词。
You pick someone up in your car, you could even pick someone up on your bicycle.
你可以开车接某人，甚至可以用自行车接某人。
That's right, that's right.
没错，没错。
So, but you can see that you can say we need to pick up Tommy at the hotel or you can say
所以，但你可以看到，你可以说“我们需要去酒店接汤米”，或者你可以说
we need to pick Tommy up.
我们需要接汤米。
So you can use it both ways.
所以两种用法都可以。
You can put the noun in between or after.
你可以把名词放在中间或后面。
So can you pick me up at five?
那么你能在五点接我吗？
Right, right.
对，对。
Or can you pick up the clothes at the dry cleaners?
或者你能去干洗店取衣服吗？
That's right.
没错。
It means to go collect something.
意思是去取某物。
That's right.
没错。
So you can use it in different ways.
所以你可以用不同的方式使用它。
You can put the noun in between pick up or you can put it after.
你可以把名词放在“pick up”中间，或者放在后面。
And all right, so they're going to go pick up Mr. Campbell.
好的，所以他们要去接坎贝尔先生。
Now they're talking, well, they're kind of gossiping a little bit.
现在他们在聊天，嗯，他们有点八卦。
They said, well, I heard you got married.
他们说，嗯，我听说你结婚了。
All right, so I heard.
好的，所以我听说。
Now this is a very, very common way to start a sentence that might have some gossip in
这是一个非常非常常见的句子开头方式，可能包含一些八卦内容
it.
。
So I'm going to say something that might or might not be true.
所以我要说一些可能真实也可能不真实的事情。
That's right.
没错。
So you're not really sure if it's true or not.
所以你不确定它是否真实。
So this is why you start with the sentence, I heard that something, something, something.
这就是为什么你用这个句子开头：“我听说某事、某事、某事”。
So in this case, you said, I heard you got married.
所以在这种情况下，你说：“我听说你结婚了。”
Or I heard you got married because I'm basically saying, well, some rumor made it to me and
或者“我听说你结婚了”，因为我基本上是在说，嗯，有些谣言传到我这里，
I heard that you got married, but I'm not sure.
我听说你结婚了，但我不确定。
So she's asking, did you get married?
所以她是在问：“你结婚了吗？”
If so, congratulations.
如果是的话，恭喜。
That's right.
没错。
So it's a very common way of starting a sentence when you are talking to someone and maybe
所以这是一个非常常见的句子开头方式，当你和某人说话时，也许
you want them to confirm this news or this gossip or this rumor is true or not.
你想让他们确认这个消息、八卦或谣言是否真实。
I heard you got a promotion.
我听说你升职了。
That's right.
没错。
Congratulations.
恭喜。
So that's the way that you use this phrase.
这就是使用这个短语的方式。
I heard you or well, if you're using another person, I heard that Tom got divorced.
我听说你，或者如果你提到另一个人，我听说汤姆离婚了。
I heard Susie had a baby.
我听说苏西生了个孩子。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So that's all for the first part of Fluency Builder.
这就是流利度构建第一部分的内容。
Let's take a break and we'll be back in a bit with part two.
我们休息一下，稍后回来继续第二部分。
Hey Michelle, jumping quick.
嘿，米歇尔，快上车。
It's pouring out there.
外面下着倾盆大雨。
Oh, hi Melissa.
哦，嗨，梅丽莎。
Are you going to the conference too?
你也要去参加会议吗？
I was planning to pick up Mr. Campbell.
我正打算去接坎贝尔先生。
Yes.
是的。
Actually, we need to pick him up at his hotel and then go to the conference.
实际上，我们需要去他的酒店接他，然后去参加会议。
Oh, I see.
哦，我明白了。
Okay.
好的。
So I heard you got married.
所以我听说你结婚了。
Congratulations.
恭喜。
Oh, thank you.
哦，谢谢。
I'm very excited.
我非常兴奋。
We were going to get married next year, but then we decided to get married on holiday
我们本来打算明年结婚，但后来决定在假期结婚
instead.
代替。
It was wonderful.
那真是太棒了。
That sounds so romantic.
听起来真浪漫。
Jack and I were hoping to get married in Europe next year, but we had to postpone our plans.
杰克和我本来希望明年在欧洲结婚，但我们不得不推迟计划。
We just don't have the money.
我们就是没钱。
I know what you mean.
我明白你的意思。
I think Shanghai is getting more and more expensive.
我觉得上海越来越贵了。
Don't you?
你不觉得吗？
I sure do.
我当然觉得。
In my opinion, it's actually becoming more expensive than back home.
在我看来，它实际上比家乡还贵。
Definitely.
绝对是。
Oh, there's Mr. Campbell.
哦，坎贝尔先生来了。
Driver, can you stop here, please?
司机，能在这里停一下吗？
All right.
好的。
So now we're back with part two of Fluency Builder.
现在我们回到流利度构建的第二部分。
Let's get started with the first phrase.
让我们从第一个短语开始。
When she says that they got married on holiday, what does that mean?
当她说他们在度假时结婚，那是什么意思？
On holiday is another way of saying on vacation.
"On holiday" 是"on vacation"的另一种说法。
So while we were having a holiday somewhere, this happened.
所以，当我们在某个地方度假时，这件事发生了。
So you could say, we decided to get married on holiday.
所以你可以说，我们决定在度假时结婚。
That means when they were traveling, when they were on vacation, they got married.
这意味着当他们旅行时，当他们度假时，他们结婚了。
So it's kind of more of a British way of saying, right?
所以这更像是英式说法，对吧？
On holiday?
"On holiday"？
Yes.
是的。
You could say, where did you go on holiday?
你可以说，你去哪里度假了？
But maybe in America, we'd prefer to say, where did you go on vacation?
但在美国，我们可能更喜欢说，你去哪里度假了？
On vacation.
"On vacation"。
So both are correct.
所以两种说法都正确。
You can say, we got married while on holiday or we got married while on vacation.
你可以说，我们在度假时结婚，或者我们在度假时结婚。
Both are correct.
两种都正确。
It's just a little bit of difference between British English and American English.
这只是英式英语和美式英语之间的一点小差异。
And then moving on, she said, well, they also wanted to get married, Michelle did, but they
然后继续，她说，嗯，他们也想要结婚，米歇尔也是，但他们不得不推迟婚礼。
had to postpone their wedding.
推迟他们的婚礼。
Okay.
好的。
To postpone something means to wait until later to do it.
"To postpone something" 意思是等到以后再去做。
So you maybe want to do it today, but it's raining today.
所以你可能今天想做，但今天下雨。
So you have to postpone until next week.
所以你不得不推迟到下周。
That's right.
没错。
So it's kind of like you had to delay, you had to wait.
所以这有点像你不得不延迟，不得不等待。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
So you could say that because of bad weather, the picnic will be postponed until next month.
所以你可以说，因为天气不好，野餐将推迟到下个月。
Okay.
好的。
So that's the way they use postpone.
所以他们就是这样使用"postpone"的。
Now it's interesting because you have a P in between there, so it's postpone.
现在有趣的是，中间有一个P，所以是"postpone"。
Postpone.
"Postpone"。
Yeah, it's an interesting word to pronounce.
是的，这是一个发音有趣的词。
Okay.
好的。
And well, they also had to postpone it because of money.
嗯，他们也因为钱的问题不得不推迟。
It's just very expensive.
只是太贵了。
And Melissa agrees by saying, I know what you mean.
梅丽莎同意说，我明白你的意思。
I know what you mean.
我明白你的意思。
Now this is a really common phrase and this is something you'll hear with more relaxed
这是一个非常常见的短语，你会听到它在朋友之间更轻松的对话中出现。
conversations between friends.
它意味着我理解情况，或者我有同感。
It means I understand the situation or I feel the same way.
所以在这种情况下，我们只是没有钱。
So in this case, we just don't have the money.
梅丽莎在说，我明白你的意思。
Melissa's saying, I know what you mean.
它意味着我也在钱上遇到困难。
It means I'm having a hard time with money too.
我也没有多少钱。
I don't have much money either.
没错。
That's right.
所以你理解她在说什么。
So you understand what she's talking about.
你也同意。
You also agree.
我明白你的意思。
I know what you mean.
这只是一种同意别人的方式。
It's just a way of agreeing with someone.
好的。
All right.
然后她继续确认米歇尔说的话，说，我觉得上海越来越贵了。
And then she goes on to confirm what Michelle is saying by saying, I think Shanghai is getting
好的。
more and more expensive.
这是一个非常关键的句子结构。
All right.
我们有"more and more"，"more and more"。
Now this is a really, really key sentence structure here.
然后后面跟一个形容词。
We have more and more, more and more.
所以结构是"more and more"加形容词。
And then after that we have an adjective.
所以"more and more spicy"，"more and more funny"，"more and more expensive"。
So the structure is more and more adjectives.
所以在这种情况下，这个城市比以前更贵了。
So more and more spicy, more and more funny, more and more expensive.
没错。
So in this case, the city is more expensive than it was before.
而且它还在变得更贵。
That's right.
没错。
And it's still getting more expensive.
当你使用这个结构时，主要意思是当你说"more and more"，然后加上一个形容词，比如"expensive"或"beautiful"，它意味着它持续增长。
That's right.
它持续变得更贵、更美或更难。
That's the main idea when you use this structure is that when you say more and more and then
但记住，我们在这里使用的形容词是当你使用比较级时，你不能说，例如，你不能用"funny"。
you add an adjective such as expensive or beautiful, it means that it continues to grow.
你不能说"you are getting more and more funny"，因为显然"funny"的比较级是"funnier"。
It continues to get more expensive or more beautiful or more difficult.
所以小心这一点，因为它可能有点让人困惑。
But remember that we are using adjectives here that are when you're using the comparative,
好的。
you can't say, for example, you can't use funny.
所以为了结束我们的流利度构建，我们有米歇尔同意梅丽莎，说，是的，你知道，我觉得上海越来越贵了。
You can't say you are getting more and more funny because obviously the comparative for
她说，"I sure do"。
funny is funnier.
所以她基本上是在同意。
So just be careful with that one because it could be a little bit confusing.
她在说，是的，那是真的。
All right.
但为什么？
So and to finish off our fluency builder, we have Michelle who agrees with Melissa and
为什么她说"I sure do"？
says, yeah, you know, I think Shanghai is getting more expensive.
为什么她不说"agree"？
And she says, I sure do.
"I agree"或"yeah, you're right"。
So she's basically agreeing.
嗯，她不必说，因为她说了"I do"。
She's saying, yes, that's true.
所以"do"在这里代替了"agree"。
But why?
所以"do"是一个替代动词。
Why does she say I sure do?
所以她说"I sure do"意思是"我确实同意"。
Why doesn't she say agree?
所以这是一种非常常见的同意方式。
I agree or yeah, you're right.
是的，没错。
Well, she doesn't have to say it because she says I do.
所以"do"可以代替许多动词。
The question before that was, I think something, something, don't you?
之前那个问题是，我觉得是，什么什么，对吧？
And she says, I do.
然后她说，我愿意。
And I think that.
我也这么觉得。
So it's assumed that she also thinks this.
所以可以认为她也这么想。
She's answering a question.
她在回答一个问题。
That's right.
没错。
So that's an interesting way of asking a question when you say, I think the city is beautiful.
所以当你问“我觉得这个城市很美”时，这是一种有趣的提问方式。
Don't you?
对吧？
So the proper way to answer that would be I do or I sure do.
所以正确的回答应该是“我愿意”或“我当然愿意”。
All right.
好了。
So that's all the time we have for fluency builder.
这就是我们流利度训练的全部时间了。
Let's listen to our dialogue one last time.
让我们最后听一遍对话。
Hey, Michelle, jumping quick.
嘿，Michelle，快跳进来。
It's pouring out there.
外面下着倾盆大雨。
Oh, hi, Melissa.
哦，嗨，Melissa。
Are you going to the conference too?
你也要去参加会议吗？
I was planning to pick up Mr. Campbell.
我本来打算去接Campbell先生。
Yes, he told me we need to pick him up at his hotel and then go to the conference.
是的，他告诉我我们需要去他酒店接他，然后去参加会议。
Oh, I see.
哦，我明白了。
OK, so I heard you got married.
好的，我听说你结婚了。
Congratulations.
恭喜。
Oh, thank you.
哦，谢谢。
I'm very excited.
我非常兴奋。
We were going to get married next year, but then we decided to get married on holiday
我们本来打算明年结婚，但后来决定在假期结婚
instead.
反而。
It was wonderful.
那真是太棒了。
That sounds so romantic.
听起来真浪漫。
Jack and I were hoping to get married in Europe next year, but we had to postpone our plans.
Jack和我本来希望明年在欧洲结婚，但我们不得不推迟计划。
We just don't have the money.
我们就是没钱。
I know what you mean.
我懂你的意思。
I think Shanghai is getting more and more expensive.
我觉得上海越来越贵了。
Don't you?
对吧？
I sure do.
我当然觉得。
In my opinion, it's actually becoming more expensive than back home.
在我看来，它实际上变得比家乡还贵。
Definitely.
绝对是。
Oh, there's Mr. Campbell.
哦，Campbell先生来了。
Driver, can you stop here, please?
司机，能在这儿停一下吗？
All right, so we're reaching the end of our small talk series.
好了，我们即将结束闲聊系列。
In this case, it's two women who are talking about their personal lives.
在这个案例中，是两个女人在谈论她们的私人生活。
And not only that, they're talking about weddings and they're talking about money.
不仅如此，她们还在谈论婚礼和钱。
So this is a very interesting way to talk about these very common topics, personal life,
所以这是一种非常有趣的方式来谈论这些非常常见的话题：私人生活、
love and especially money.
爱情，尤其是钱。
But remember, in American culture, these are the kinds of things you would only talk to
但记住，在美国文化中，这些是你只会和
your friends about.
朋友谈论的事情。
You wouldn't really want to talk to strangers about money, personal life, marriage, because
你不会真的想和陌生人谈论钱、私人生活、婚姻，因为
those are considered private.
这些被认为是私密的。
So be careful when you're talking to people you don't know very well.
所以当你和不太熟悉的人交谈时要小心。
That's right.
没错。
And actually, your feedback was very interesting when we discussed about if it's okay to ask,
实际上，当我们讨论是否适合问，比如，一个女人的年龄或体重或一个男人的薪水时，你的反馈非常有趣。
for example, a woman her age or her weight or a man's salary.
在大多数地方，你说这不太合适。
So in most places, you said that it wasn't really correct.
但这是关于文化差异和什么适合
But this is the very interesting thing about the cultural differences and what is appropriate
谈论的非常有趣的一点。
to talk about.
没错。
That's right.
所以再次强调，如果你对我们今天讨论的内容或我们关于闲聊的旧课程有任何问题或评论，
So again, if you have any questions or comments about the things we talked about here today
请告诉我们。
or any of our older lessons about small talk, please just let us know.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
好了，各位。
All right, guys.
我们那儿见。
We'll see you there.
感谢收看Polish English。
And thanks for watching Polish English.
好了。